Guide to the Speeches and Articles by and about Presidents of Yale University
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Speeches and articles by and about presidents of Yale University
1960-1993
RU 65
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
The records consist of biographical material, speeches, interviews, and television transcripts by or about Kingman Brewster, Jr., A. Bartlett Giamatti, Benno C. Schmidt and Howard Lamar as presidents of Yale University.
Yale University. Office of Public Affairs
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of biographical material, speeches, interviews, and television transcripts by or about Kingman Brewster, Jr., A. Bartlett Giamatti, Benno C. Schmidt and Howard Lamar as presidents of Yale University.
College presidents; Educators; Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1919-1988; Giamatti, A. Bartlett, 1938-1989; Lamar, Howard Roberts, 1923-; Schmidt, Benno C., 1942-; Yale University -- Presidents; Yale University. Office of Public Affairs; Yale University. President's Office
- Speeches and articles concerning A. Bartlett Giamatti, 1960-1987; Accession 1988-A-054
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Official Biographical (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - current Biography, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - who's who Current Biography, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Honorary Degrees, Awards, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Family and career prior to Election, 1932-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Quotations, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Articles, Speeches prior to Election, 1960-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Story of Italy" - TV program, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Entire Affection Hateth Nicer Hands" - Article, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Article: "Viewpoints", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Article: "The Writing Gap" "Sentimentality", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Article: "Hyperbole's Child: Muhammeh Ali", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Tom Seaver's Farewell", 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "The Green Fields of the Mind", 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Election as 19th President, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Yale Alumni Journal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Annual Report" Letter, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Time Magazine, 1978 January 2 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Yale Daily News (Fake Issue), 1978 January 2 (Box 1, Folder 19a)
  - Yale Drama School, Dean Brustein, 1978 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - statement, 1978 June (Box 1, Folder 20a)
  - Freshman Assembly Address, 1978 sep 5 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Yale Daily News: Inaugural Issue, 1978 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Inauguration, 1978 oct 14 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Yale Daily News: Inauguration Issue, 1978 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Article: "Going Home", 1978 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Recall, as the Series Ends, the Afternoon of the Fall" - The Harford Courant, 1978 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine: "A New Administration", 1978 October (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine: Inauguration, 1978 November (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - New England Magazine, The Boston Globe, 1978 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - University Council: 30th Anniversary, 1978 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Interview: The Hartford Courant, 1978 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - The New York Times: Liberal Arts, 1978 December 11 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Modern Language Association of America, 1978 December 28 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Remarks, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 33a)
  - Interviews, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Context (DuPont), No. 1, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Yale and Greater New Haven Salute Dinner, 1979 January 6 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Yale Club of Washington, D. C, 1979 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Federal Regulation and Public Interest, 1979 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - C. Rathbone: Interview, 1979 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Headmaster's Association, 1979 February 9 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Yale Club of Houston, 1979 February 15 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Yale Club of Dallas, 1979 February 16 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Senate Hearing on Curriculum, 1979 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Hew-Cohen-Fleming Lecture, 1979 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Yale Club of Philadelphia, 1979 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Investor Responsibility, 1979 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Resignation: Provost Abraham S. Goldstein, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Baccalaureate Address, 1979 May 20 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Interview: The New York Times, 1979 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Profile: The New Haven Register, 1979 July 22 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Time: 50 Fares for the Future, 1979 August 6 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Freshman Assembly Address, 1979 September 3 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - United Way: Kick Off, 1979 September 19 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Tenure: Letter to Yale College Council, 1979 September 20 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - The Today Show, 1979 September 20 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - School of Organization and Management Dedication, 1979September 29 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Yale Club of Western New York, 1979 October 12 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, 1979October 13 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Law School Alumni Luncheon, 1979 October 20 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Sports Section: The New Haven Register, 1979 October 21 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Firing Line: William F. Buckley, 1979 October 30 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Independent Colleges of Southern California, 1979 November 27 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Yale Club of San Diego, 1979 November 27 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Yale Club of Portland, 1979 November 28 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Yale Club of Western Washington, 1979 November 28 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - The Commercial Club of Boston: The Merchant's Club, 1979 December 11 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Article in The Los Angeles Times, 1979 December 26 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Statements: Budget, Term Bill, Tuition, Compensation, 1980 January (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Yale Club of Chicago, 1980 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - The New Haven Register: "Local" Sports, 1980 January 29 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Sports: Heroes for the Sports Pages, 1980 February 2 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - The New Haven Register (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Statement: Politics - Ronald Reagan's Campaign, 1980February 10 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Statement: Affirmative Action, 1980 February 29 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Annual Report: The American Teacher, 1980March (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Yale Daily News: The President (5 part series), 1980 April (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - New Haven Journal-Courier: Interview, 1980 April 4 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Athletics: Ivy Sports, Recruiting and Scheduling, 1980April 10 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Atlanta Constitution: Hal Gulliver, 1980 April 29-30 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Union: Local 35, 1980 May 1 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Contract Settlement, 1980 May 1 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Yale Club of Pittsburgh, 1980 May 9 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Sports: Red Sox, The Hartford Courant, 1980 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - The New York Times: Top Marks at Yale, 1980 May 22 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Baccalaureate Address, 1980 May 25 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Colorado Yale Association, 1980 June 11 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Yale Club of Kansas City, MO, 1980 June 12 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Yale Club of Utah, 1980 June 13 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Sports: Bristol Valley Press, 1980 June 26 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Harper's: "The American Teacher", undated (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Freshman Address, 1980 September 2 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Edith Wharton: Commemorative Stamp Dedication, 1980 September 5 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Graduate-Professional Schools Assembly Address, 1980September 9 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - New Haven Register: "Giamatti:Politicians Snub Education", 1980 September 23 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - New Haven Register: Alumni Visits, 1980 September 28 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Yale Alumni Fund: 90th Birthday Convocation, 1980 October 3 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Hartford Courant: A Tough Job Grows on Yale's Giamatti, 1980 October 5 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Library Celebration: Sterling Memorial Library, 1980October 10 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Yale Daily News, 1980October 16 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Science and the University, 1980 October 16 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - The New Haven Boys' Club Dinner, 1980 October 17 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - New Haven Register: Giamatti Settles in at Yale (2 1/2 years at Yale), 1980 October 26 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Honorary Degree: The Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1980 November 2 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Yale Daily News Magazine, 1980 December 11 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Editor and Publisher Magazine: New England Society Newspaper Editors, 1980 December 13 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - The University and the Public Interest, Athenium, NY, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Attenzione, 1981January (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Governor's Conference on Excellence in Educatio, 1981January 23 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Whitney Humanities Center, 1981 February 4 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Connecticut Travels: Yale's President on Regulations, 1981 February (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - The Washington Post, 1981 March 10 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Sports Illustrated: "A desire to Excel", 1981 March 30 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Annual Report 1980-1981, 1981 April (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Yale Daily News: Federal Budget, 1981 April (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - AYA Assembly XVIII New Haven/ Yale: On Common Ground, 1981 May 7 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Atlanta University Commencement, 1981 May 18 (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Atlanta Constitution: "Yale's Giamatti: A Sense of History", 1981 May 26 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Baccalaureate Address, 1981 May 23 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - The Boston Globe (Yale-New Haven), 1981 May 23 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Time: Commencement, 1981June 15 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Letter to the Makers of Baseball, 1981 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - The New York Times: "Men of Baseball, Lend an Ear", 1981 June 16 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Boston Chronicle: "Men of Baseball, Enough is Enough", 1981 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Rocky Mountain News, Co.: "Baseball is a Trust", 1981 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - New York, NY; News: "Man here says he's tired of baseball--and its poets", 1981 June 23 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Dartmouth College: Inauguration Day, 1981 June 28 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - The New York Times: About Education, 1981 June 7 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - The New Yorker: The Sporting Scene, 1981 July 20 (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - The New York Times: "The Strike and the Things We've Lost", 1981 July 26 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - National Commission on Excellence in Education, 1981August (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Freshman Assembly Address, 1981 August 31 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - The New Haven Advocate: "The Old School Tie", 1981 October 14 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Yale Law School Alumni Luncheon, 1981 October 17 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - AYA Assembly Dinner, 1981 October 22 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Cincinatti Yale Club Dinner, 1981 November 18 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Making Good; Jane Adams, William Morrow and Co., Inc., 1981 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - New England Society of Newspaper Editors, 1981 December 4-6 (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - Yale Club of San Francisco, 1982 January 7 (Box 7, Folder 137)
  - Avon High School Dedication Ceremony, 1982 January 24 (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - The New Journal: Moral Majority, 1982 January 30 (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - Selected Recent Reports and Studies on American Schools, 1982 February (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - The Yale Daily News Magazine, 1982 February 2 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - The New York Times: "A Dead Language is Given a Lively Defense", 1982 February 9 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Obituary: Valentine Giamatti (Father), 1982 March 17 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - The College Board Review, 1982 spring (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - The Yale Club of Montclair, NJ, 1982 April 2 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Yale Alumni in the Nation's Leadership, 1982 April 20 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Annual Report of the President: 1981-1982, 1982May (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Baccalaureate Address: "In the Midde Distance", 1982May 23 (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - College of New Rochelle, 1982 May 30 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - Freshman Address, 1982 September 2 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Yale Graduate and Professional Schools Assembly, 1982September 7 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Second Circuit Judicial Conference, 1982 September 10 (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - The Role of the Federal Government in Higher Education, 1981 October 1 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - Yale Daily News: New Haven Issue, 1982 October 12 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - The Boston Globe: Higher Education Outlook Grim, 1982 October 20 (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - Honolulu Advertiser: "Giamatti: Key to Unlocking Yale Minds", 1982 October 25 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - American College of Surgeons, 1982 October 28 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Yale Art Gallery: 150th Anniversary Celebration, 1982October 30 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - Poland: Solidarity, 1982 November (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - New Haven Advocate: Biagio DiLieto-Mayor, 1982 November 17 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Legal Times, 1982 November 29 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - Free Market and Free Inquiry: the University, Industry, and Cooperative Research, the University of Pennsylvania, 1982 December 15 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Science: American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1982 December 24 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Interview: The New Haven Register, 1982 December 26 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Draft Registration and Financial Aid, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Connecticut Magazine: The Power People, 1983 January (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - New Haven Register-Parade: "How College Students Have Changed", 1983 February 20 (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - Yale Club Speech, 1983 March (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - The New York Times Sunday Magazine, 1983 March 6 (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges, 1983 Mar/April (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - The New York Times Magazine: "Italian Americans", 1983 May 15 (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - New Haven Advocate: "Yale's Labor Pains", 1983 May 18 (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - Commencement: Baccalaureate Address, 1983 May 22 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - Louis Sudler Prize, 1983 June 6 (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - Princeton Day School Commencement, 1983 June 12 (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - Freshman Assembly, 1983 September 5 (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - E.L. Miller Lecture: Texas A & M University, 1983 October 5 (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - Columbus Day Dinner: Park Plaza Hotel, 1983 October 8 (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - Albertus Magnus College Inauguration, 1983 October 15 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Residential Colleges: 50th Anniversary, 1983 October 21 (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Hartford Courant: "Giamatti Stands by Yale's Policies, 1983 December 11 (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - "Bart Giamatti" Radio Spot, New Haven Chamber of Commerce, 1983 December (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Elizabethan Club, 1984 January 26 (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Exile and Change in Renaissance Literature: Yale University Press, 1984February (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Term Bill, 1984 February 8 (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Greenwich High School, 1984 February 9 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - "Yale's Giamatti" The Day (New London), 1984 February 12 (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - American Friends of Tel Aviv University, Boca Raton, FL, 1984 March 17 (Box 9, Folder 188)
  - Union: Local 34 Clerical/Technical, 1984 March 22 (Box 9, Folder 189)
  - Baccalaureate Address: "Give Time to Time", 1984 May 27 (Box 9, Folder 190)
  - Connoisseur Magazine, 1984 June (Box 9, Folder 191)
  - Elm-Ivy Awards Luncheon, 1984 June 6 (Box 9, Folder 192)
  - College of Staten Island Commencement Speech, 1984 June 10 (Box 9, Folder 193)
  - Note-Selling Article; New Haven Register, 1984 June 11 (Box 9, Folder 194)
  - Profile: New Haven Magazine, 1984 June (Box 9, Folder 195)
  - Freshman Address: "Education and the Pleasures of Paradox", 1984 September 3 (Box 9, Folder 196)
  - Remarks: Graduate and Professional Assembly, 1984 September 10 (Box 9, Folder 197)
  - "An Education for Freedom" Holocaust Memorial Council Conference, 1984 September 19 (Box 9, Folder 198)
  - New York Times: "Yale Chief Discusses Issue in Strike", 1984 October 12 (Box 9, Folder 199)
  - New Haven Register: Interview regarding Strike, 1984 October 24 (Box 9, Folder 200)
  - CPTB Interview, 1984 November 7 (Box 9, Folder 201)
  - Ferdinand Phinizy Lectures: University of Georgia, 1985January 22 (Box 9, Folder 202)
  - Atlanta Constitution: "Yale President Blasts Reagan on Education", 1985 February 22 (Box 9, Folder 203)
  - President of Yale to speak at Ballard, 1985 March 13 (Box 9, Folder 204)
  - Testimony before Subcommittee on Education, Arts and Humanities, Senate Labor and Human Resources Committee, 1985 March 29 (Box 9, Folder 205)
  - Students, Administrators decry "hope-slashing" U.S. aid cut proposal, 1985 March 30 (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - Boston Sunday Globe: "A Magic Game and an End to Innocence" (Gammon's Book Review), 1985 April 7 (Box 9, Folder 207)
  - Journal-Courier: "Half of Yale's Students Would Be Hurt by Cuts", 1985 April 8 (Box 9, Folder 208)
  - New Haven Register: "Yale Students Protest Aid Cuts", 1985 April 10 (Box 9, Folder 209)
  - Signet Society, 1985 April 11 (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - Transcript of Resignation Announcement, 1985 April 22 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Articles on Resignation, 1985 April (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - New Haven Register: Intensive Search Begins for Giamatti's Successor, 1985 April 23 (Box 10, Folder 213)
  - Baccalaureate Address, 1985 May 23 (Box 10, Folder 214)
  - Class of 1960, 25th Reunion, 1985 May 31 (Box 10, Folder 215)
  - Choate Rosemary Hall commencement, 1985 June 9 (Box 10, Folder 216)
  - Boston Sunday Globe: "Yale's President Giamatti a Forever Young Thinker", 1985 June 9 (Box 10, Folder 217)
  - Interview: "Sunday Morning" - CBS, 1985 June 9 (Box 10, Folder 218)
  - The Christian Science Monitor: "To Giamatti Education Isn't Job Training", 1985 June 21 (Box 10, Folder 219)
  - Testimony of Yale University before the Legislative Committee of the New Haven Board of Aldermen, 1985 June 25 (Box 10, Folder 220)
  - The Christian Science Monitor: "Why Diamonds Aren't a Ball-Players Best Friend", 1985 August 9 (Box 10, Folder 221)
  - The New Haven Register: Yale President "Fair" After Kidney Surgery, 1985 August 26 (Box 10, Folder 222)
  - President of Yale Ponders Campaign for Senate Seat, 1985 August 30 (Box 10, Folder 223)
  - WNBC-TV 4: Editorial "Giamatti for Senator", 1985 August 30 (Box 10, Folder 224)
  - Freshman Address, 1985 August 31 (Box 10, Folder 225)
  - New Haven Register: "Giamatti Tells Freshmen to Keep Mind Open", 1985 September 1 (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - A Brief History of Albertus Magnus College, 1985 September 21 (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - The Boston Globe: "Yale's President Says He's Mulling a Run for Dodd's Senate Seat", 1985 September 25 (Box 10, Folder 228)
  - WNET-TV 13 Education Program: "Benny Goodman - 'Let's Dance' - A Musical Tribute", 1985 October 7 (Box 10, Folder 229)
  - "Baseball and the American Character" Massachussetts Historical Society at the Boston Public Library, 1985 October 17 (Box 10, Folder 230)
  - The Boston Globe: "Talking Baseball at the BPL", 1985 October 19 (Box 10, Folder 231)
  - The Boston Sunday Globe: "Yale President Giamatti Says He Won't Run For Senate", 1985 November 5 (Box 10, Folder 232)
  - "New Haven and Yale" - Union Trust Dinner, 1985 November 8 (Box 10, Folder 233)
  - New Haven Register: "Yale's Presidential List Down to 20 Candidates", 1985 November 17 (Box 10, Folder 234)
  - Speech: Yale Daily News (Special Harvard Edition), 1985 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 235)
  - Journal-Courier: "Panel Agrees in Love of Baseball", 1986 February 12 (Box 10, Folder 236)
  - Yale Library Associates Dinner: "Figures for Writing and Books in Antiquity and the Renaissance", 1986 February 21 (Box 10, Folder 237)
  - The New Journal: "The Power and the President: Giamatti's Years at Yale", 1986 February 28 (Box 10, Folder 238)
  - Yale Daily News: "The Giamatti Years", 1986 April (Box 10, Folder 239)
  - Journal-Courier: "Giamatti Blasts Press", 1986 April 2 (Box 10, Folder 240)
  - New Haven Register: "Giamatti Still Open to State Politics", 1986 April 2 (Box 10, Folder 241)
  - Humanities and the Public Interest: Transcript of Symposium (Giamatti - Poderetz), 1986 April 5 (Box 10, Folder 242)
  - New Haven Register: "Yale Shanties May Rise Again. Giamatti Defends His Administration's Handling of Protest", 1986 April 19 (Box 10, Folder 243)
  - The New York Times: "Farewell Dinner to Honor Yale's Giamatti", 1986 April 20 (Box 10, Folder 244)
  - New Haven Register: "Social Spotlight Shines Old Blue", 1986 April 20 (Box 10, Folder 245)
  - Journal-Courier: "Stored Memorial Smashed in Error, Giamatti Says", 1986 April 25 (Box 10, Folder 246)
  - Journal-Courier: "Politics Mixes with Celebrations of Giamatti-DiLieto Chess Game", 1986 April 28 (Box 10, Folder 247)
  - New Haven Register: "Protestors Push Points During Giant Chess Game", 1986 April 28 (Box 10, Folder 248)
  - The Nutmegger: "'Leave When You're Ahead': Yale's Giamatti on Retiring", 1986 May (Box 10, Folder 249)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine: University: The President's Years, An Interview with A. Bartlett Giamatti, 1986 May (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - New Haven Register: "Friends Land Giamatti in Farewell", 1986 May 4 (Box 10, Folder 251)
  - Journal-Courier: "1000 Remember Holocaust at Memorial Service", 1986 May 5 (Box 10, Folder 252)
  - New Haven Register: "Town and Gown Toasts Bart Giamatti", 1986 May 11 (Box 10, Folder 253)
  - 1985 Special Elm-Ivy Award, 1986 May 15 (Box 10, Folder 254)
  - Journal-Courier: "Giamatti Given Medal (Barnard College)", 1986 May 20 (Box 10, Folder 255)
  - Baccalaureate Address, 1986 May 25 (Box 11, Folder 256)
  - Hartford Courant: "Giamatti Extols Liberal Education", 1986 May 26 (Box 11, Folder 257)
  - New York Times: "Commencement Ceremonies: Words of Farewell - Yale University - Last Speech for Giamatti as President", 1986 May 26 (Box 11, Folder 258)
  - The Boston Globe: "Commencements: Giamatti Presides Over His Final Graduation at Yale", 1986 May 27 (Box 11, Folder 259)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine: "Baccalaureate: Ruminations on Congregations, Their Pleasures and Perils", 1986 June (Box 11, Folder 260)
  - New York Times: "Giamatti Likely National League Chief", 1986 June 6 (Box 11, Folder 261)
  - New Haven Register: "Baseball Eyes Giamatti for Jump to Big League", 1986 June 6 (Box 11, Folder 262)
  - New Haven Register: "Giamatti Could Get NL Job by Next Week", 1986 June 7 (Box 11, Folder 263)
  - Hartford Courant: "Giamatti: From Yale to NL?", 1986 June 7 (Box 11, Folder 264)
  - The Boston Globe: "Baseball: Giamatti to be Named Today?", 1986 June 10 (Box 11, Folder 265)
  - Journal-Courier: "Giamatti 'Up' as NL Proxy", 1986 June 10 (Box 11, Folder 266)
  - Hartford Courant: "Psst, Here's the Scoop on Why Giamatti Decided Against the Senate", 1986June 10 (Box 11, Folder 267)
  - Journal-Courier: "Giamatti is Out of his League with This Job" (George Wadley's Viewpoint), 1986June 10 (Box 11, Folder 268)
  - The Hartford Courant: "Yale's Giamatti is Expected to Get NL Top Job Today", 1986 June 10 (Box 11, Folder 269)
  - New Haven Register: "Giamatti Warms Up for NL Job", 1986 June 10 (Box 11, Folder 270)
  - New Haven Register: "A Defferent Kind of President", 1986 June 11 (Box 11, Folder 271)
  - The New York Times: "From Dante to Darling" by Ira Bertow, 1986 June 11 (Box 11, Folder 272)
  - New Haven Register: "Giamatti on Baseball: Diamonds of Wisdom", 1986 June 11 (Box 11, Folder 273)
  - The Boston Globe: "Giamatti Named NL President", 1986 June 11 (Box 11, Folder 274)